<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Paulo da Corte</title>
    <link>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Paulo da Corte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 01:39:39 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Earning the Sunset</title>
      <link>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/earningsunset/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 01:39:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/earningsunset/</guid>
      <description>The merchants among us are well versed in the art of comercialising their time. Whatever activity it is, if there&amp;rsquo;s a byproduct, there&amp;rsquo;s a market for it.
Then, marketing it comes in play, this shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the case before the production is streamlined. This is usually done with the passion of a hobbyist.
I too need to follow this archetype and build a basis for value creation, and its tied fortune, that is not bound to the whims of an external party.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consistency</title>
      <link>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/consistency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 21:48:25 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/consistency/</guid>
      <description>When I do something that goes with the dulling of my mind, regret sets in. Is it not my chief office the duty to keep my body ready and my mind sharp? Is overeating, lethargy, laziness and other general ways of avoiding work not an obvious enemy to who I want to become? Yes, they are, so, therefore, I should do the following simple commandments:
Protect energy at all costs: Exercise and stretch Walk daily Do not overeat Be consistent with the behaviours that bring traction Learn and read Execute on personal projects Create bonds that will help you become this person you want to become Socialize when possible Seek out creators and create yourself Have something that can be a window into who you are I&amp;rsquo;ve been feeling the brevity of time a bit more accutely lately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling Traction</title>
      <link>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/modelling_traction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2023 11:40:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/modelling_traction/</guid>
      <description>Frameworks and Models While searching for tools to help me be consistent, even when my body is sapped, I&amp;rsquo;ve come across a model that can be used to describe the elements of traction.
Energy + Clarity + Willpower * Focus = Traction/Output
Let&amp;rsquo;s expand on these elements by breaking them down.
Elements Gained by Spent By Energy True Rest (Meditation/Napping/Deep Sleep) Everything Else / Task Switching Clarity Writing down your objectives - The more precise and granular, the clearer / Maintaining Good Posture Not being diligent, not being constant Willpower Visualization / Avoiding Excess (Food, Stimuli) / Meditation / Exercise Using Devices / Sugars / Alcohol / Mistreating your body and mind So, from this table it becomes clear that each element of this equation is negatively or positively affected by actions that we take in our everyday life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distraction</title>
      <link>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/distraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 18:23:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/distraction/</guid>
      <description>Escaping distraction is something that is so deeply important in order to get anything of true importance done, yet gets no highlight during this mighty age of distraction we live in. The big business of etnertainment has grown gigantic and must pay its figureheads, that are accustomed to exceedingly large paychecks.
Entertainment at scale, they say, is their way to bring value. And some of that value is, indeed, valuable. There are a ton of talented personalites out there that warrant your attention, but there&amp;rsquo;s a limit to everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mid March</title>
      <link>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/midmarch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 23:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/midmarch/</guid>
      <description>This blog a day concept is definitely a great idea. It&amp;rsquo;s good to check in with yourself and to put out your mind in a way that is both comprehensive and easy to reference. The issue comes with doing the same things over and over. I believe that once you&amp;rsquo;re overstimulated, rituals become more difficult to uphold. The feeling of dopamine provided by successfully completing a ritual isn&amp;rsquo;t comparable to playing video games, eating junk food or watching porn, although rituals promote better mental health and long-term well being.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early March</title>
      <link>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/early_march/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 20:02:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/early_march/</guid>
      <description>Embodiment Imagine you want to be someone who is an expert at something, says, writing or video. What if you acted as if you&amp;rsquo;re that person. You&amp;rsquo;d fail at first, but you&amp;rsquo;d quickly move towards the person you want to be. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t do this, due to perfectionism or any other reason, your progress would suffer. It would be suboptimal at this point not to embody who you want to be, because to act as that person you&amp;rsquo;d need to constantly hone yourself in that direction, which is something your current self doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre March Traction</title>
      <link>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/pre-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 22:29:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/pre-march/</guid>
      <description>Fall Down And here we go again, we&amp;rsquo;re closing in on March. For most people, this equates to milder weather and growing vegetation, but as the month of my birth, it has a special meaning to me. I&amp;rsquo;m turning 29 soon, and am yet to achieve anything of true significance in my life. I notice that the amount of time spent on distractions is on the thousands of hours. In fact, anything that can mildly represent my goals and aspirations has taken a back seat for the better part of the last few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Meditation #4</title>
      <link>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/daily_meditation_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 02:16:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/daily_meditation_4/</guid>
      <description>Writing a daily thought before bed. That was quite the long day. Energy comes from maintaining a routine and tending to our bodies, something that was certainly not respected today. I need to enforce stricter boundaries.
The quote that stuck with me from yesterday was &amp;ldquo;Your mind is mde for having ideas, not holding them&amp;rdquo;. Studying programming and other technical things has me in this neurotic state to maintain things in my head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gumption Building</title>
      <link>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/gumption_building/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 03:31:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/gumption_building/</guid>
      <description>New Machine I&amp;rsquo;ve got a new computer and a whole new setup.
I have to admit, at first I thought that building a computer was a dumb idea due to the added stress and risk. I did think that way all the way through my initial problems, such as misconnected motherboard cables, but once he was fully set up, I fell in love with this thing I built. The fact that it functions far beyond what I expected is only the cherry on top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 3</title>
      <link>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/day_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:18:39 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/day_3/</guid>
      <description>Not being as consistent as I should with my reading and writing. It is hard to stay productive when there are so many distractions, which are satisfying but end up undermining true progress.
It&amp;rsquo;s good to push something, even if small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes Taken on a SQL Course</title>
      <link>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/sql_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 20:56:26 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/sql_notes/</guid>
      <description>I take notes using Jupyter Notebooks, so this blog format is ideal.
Creating a Table Notation CREATE TABLE &amp;#34;Table name&amp;#34; ( Id char(10) PRIMARY KEY, Brand char(10) NOT NULL, Type char(250) NOT NULL, Price decimal(8,2) NOT NULL, Desc Varchar(750) NULL ); Null values accept everything. Null doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean empty string (Spaces, for example)
Inserting data into table You list all the columns that you&amp;rsquo;ll be filling and with what.
INSERT INTO &amp;#34;Table name&amp;#34; (Id ,Brand ,Type ,Price , Desc ) VALUES (&amp;#39;123456&amp;#39; ,&amp;#39;Gucci&amp;#39; ,&amp;#39;Slippers&amp;#39; ,&amp;#39;695.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day 1</title>
      <link>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/day_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 20:17:04 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pdacorte.github.io/posts/day_1/</guid>
      <description>Hey, a blog that uses markdown!
Is this some kind of subheader Markdown is good. Fast and stuff.
I wonder what this looks like Or is it too small
Subheader 3 Listicle sauce fantastic import sauce for s in sauce: eat the sauce print(s) </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
